Register of the Japan, Koshikan (Korea) records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 41-nen denju ji ichigatsu itaru shigatsu), Jan. - Apr. 1908; 50 frames. (Reel 12)
  Telegrams received by the Residency-General from Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and others relating to the recognition of alien property rights in Korea; the bill concerning the creation of Toyo Takushoku Kaisha; the assassination of Durham White Stevens in San Francisco by Koreans; and the Bethell affair. Jan. 9 - Apr. 28, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 890. 45, 46 in English.
- Documents relating to the secret orders and instructions, (Meiji 40, 41-nen kimitsu meirei kunrei shorui), 1907 - 1908; 110 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 285.
  Documents relating to Sino-Japanese negotiations for the settlement of the Korean-Manchurian boundary; Japanese military activity in Korea; Japanese policy for the suppression of popular uprisings in northeastern Korea; and the protection of Koreans in Kando (Chientao). July 23, 1907 - Sept. 9, 1909.
  Missing frame: 17. Illegible fr.: 106. Each frame is also numbered 877. 28, 29, 34b, 35a, 78-83 in Korean.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 41-nen denju ji nigatsu itaru shigatsu), Feb. - Apr. 1908; 36 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 286.
  Telegrams exchanged between Resident-General Ito and Deputy Resident-General Sone relating to the opening of Ch'0ngjin; anti-American sentiment in Korea in connection with ill treatment of Koreans in America; the increase of streetcar fares by the American Korean Electric Company in Seoul; and Chinese interests along the Yalu River. A letter from Durham White Stevens to Prince Ito; Stevens' subsequent death and the trial of his assassins. Dec. 10, 1907 - Apr. 11, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 889. 24b, 25 in English.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 41-nen denju ji jugatsu itaru junigatsu), Oct. - Dec. 1908; 66 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 287.
  Telegrams received by the Japanese Residency-General from Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and Chief of the Kando (Chientao) branch office of the Residency-General Saito Kishiro relating to the clash between the Chinese and the Japanese police in Kando and subsequent developments. Oct. 6 - Dec. 8, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 893.
- Reports of the Residency-General [to Resident-General Ito] during [his] official trip to Tokyo, (Meiji 40, 41-nen Tokanfu hokoku Tokyo shutchochu), 1907 - 1908; 25 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 288.
  Confidential note dated Nov. 28, 1907 from Resident-General Ito to Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu relating to the legal status of the Koreans acquiring citizenship abroad. Confidential reports sent to Resident-General Ito in Tokyo by Deputy Resident-General Sone relating to a plan of an American firm in Shanghai to smuggle rifles and ammunition into Korea to aid anti-Japanese insurgents. Jan. 16, 1908.
  Missing frame: 15. Each frame is also numbered 876. 22b, 23a, 24b in Korean.
- Copies of telegrams sent, (Meiji 41-nen denso hikae), 1908; 58 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 289.
  Telegrams to and from Resident-General Ito and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and others relating to Korean newspapers published in San Francisco and Vladivostok; and precautionary measures taken by the Japanese in anticipation of insurrections that might follow the abolition of Korean armed forces. Documents relating to Pak Y0ng-hyo and Ernest T Bethell. May 1 - July 30, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 895. 36b, 37 in English.
- Telegrams sent, (Meiji 41-nen denso ji hachigatsu itaru kugatsu), Aug. - Sept. 1908; 118 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 290.
  Telegraphic correspondence of Deputy Resident-General Sone with Resident-General Ito and Japanese Foreign Ministers Komura and General Terauchi Masatake relating to Ernest T. Bethell and his associates Yi P0m-yun, and Yang Ki-t'aek. Aug. 2 - Sept. 26, 1908.
  Illegible frame: 48a. Each frame is also numbered 896. 54b, 58a, 59a, 64b, 65a, 71, 81 in English.
- Telegrams sent, (Meiji 41-nen denso ji jugatsu itaru junigatsu), Oct. - Dec. 1908; 23 frames. (Reel 19)
  Box/Folder 5: 291.
  Telegrams of Deputy Resident-General Sone to Resident-General Ito concerning political conditions and popular uprisings in Korea; the clash between Japanese and Chinese troops in Kando (Chientao); the activities of Ernest T. Bethell; and Ch0n My0ng-un and Chang In-hwan, the assassins of Durham White Stevens. Oct. 7 - Dec. 5, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 897.
- Telegrams sent, (Meiji 41-nen denso ji ichigatsu itaru shigatsu), Jan. - Apr. 1908; 64 frames. (Reel n/a)
  Box/Folder 5: 292.
  Telegrams of Deputy Resident-General Sone and others to Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and others concerning the activities of the New York Export and Import Trading Company in Shanghai in the smuggling of weapons and ammunition into Korea; the ownership of a strip of land along the Yalu River by a Japanese; the death of Durham White Stevens; and the changes in the membership of the Korean Privy Council. Jan. 4 - April 22, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 894.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 41-nen denju), 1908; 122 frames. (Reel 12)
  Box/Folder 5: 293.
  Telegrams from Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu to Resident-General Ito relating to the affairs of the Korean League in San Francisco, and Bishop Harris; the Root Takahira agreement between Japan and the United States and Anglo-Japanese relations in regard to Korea. Documents relating to popular uprising in the Hesanjin area; student riots in Iju; Russian-trained rebels under the leadership of Yi P0m yun; and Sino-Japanese negotiations regarding Manchuria as a sanctuary for the Korean rebels. May 1 - July 28, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 891. 1, 2, 15b-19, 37b-39 in English.
- Documents relating to newly operated railroads, (Meiji 42-nen shin'ei tetsudo ikken), 1909; 81 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 295.
  Documents of the Residency-General relating to new railroad construction plans between Seoul and W0nsan, and Taej0n and Kunsan. Sept. 15 - Nov. 17, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 940. 23 contains a table.
- Records of the Imperial tour in northwest [Korea], (Meiji 42-nen seihoku junkoshi), 1909; 80 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 296.
  Illegible frames: 8b, 9a, 24a, 25b. Each frame is also numbered 942. 25-27a in Korean; 17 in English.
- File of proposals, (Meiji 40-nen, do 42-nen gengi tsuzuri), 1907 and 1909; 87 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 297.
  Confidential correspondence between Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and Resident-General Ito relating to the legal status of foreigners in Korea and their property rights; and the protection of railroad lines in Korea. Documents relating to the Sino-Japanese convention for the settlement of Korean-Manchurian boundary. Texts of an agreement between Ito and Korean Prime Minister Yi Wan-yong regarding the implementation of the Korean-Japanese Treaty of July 24, 1907. Jan. 18, 1908 - Feb. 15, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 939. Two different frames numbered 76. 16-18 in Korean; 19-22 in English.
- Miscellaneous file, (Meiji 42-nen zassan ji ichigatsu itaru shigatsu), Jan. - Apr. 1909; 16 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 298.
  Communications between Resident-General Ito and Deputy Resident-General Sone. Feb. 23 - Mar. 9, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 946.
- Class A documents of the Department of Archives [and] extra 8 sheets, (Meiji 40-nen koshu Bunshobu bangai 8 sheets [sic]), 1907; 91 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 299.
  Texts of an agreement between Japan and Korea regarding the Yalu River and Tumen River forestry administration and confidential correspondence between Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and Resident-General Ito relating to it. Documents relating to the popular uprising in North Ky0ngsang Province. Sept. 22, 1906 - Aug. 30, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 812. Eight "extra" frames follow 83. 4 and 5, and 47 and 48 respectively are identical. 20 b, 21a contain tables. 3a, 4a, 5a, 45a, 46a, 47a, 48a, "extra" 7 and 8 in English; 15, 16, 27b, 28 in Korean.
- Documents concerning Prince Ito, (Meiji 42-nen Ito Ko kankei shorui), 1909; 25 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 300.
  Korean Imperial decree of Nov. 4, 1909 concerning the death of Prince Ito. Confidential report of 2d Lt. Sugiyama Kyo of the Japanese gendarmerie concerning the interrogation of Prince Ito's assassin, An Chung-gun. Dec. 20, 1910.
  Each frame is also numbered 956. 7 difficult to read. 25th frame (unnumbered) is in English; 1-7 in Korean.
- Documents relating to the Korean Emperor's tour in the west (Meiji 42-nen Kanko seijun kankei shorui), 1909; 187 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 301.
  Documents relating to the tour of Emperor Sunjong in northwestern Korea. Jan. - Feb. 1909.
  Missing frame: 110. Illegible fr.: 73, 76, 77, 79, 88. Each frame is also numbered 960. 46-60, 74, 75, 78, 79 contain tables and plans; 70-72, 86 contain maps.
- Copies of telegrams received, (Meiji 42-nen denju hikae tsuzuri), 1909; 82 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 302.
  Telegrams sent to Resident-General Sone by Japanese Foreign Minister Komura and others relating to the Sino-Japanese settlement of the Korean-Manchurian boundary; and the floating of bonds of South Manchuria Railway Company. Sept. 2 - Oct. 15, 1909.
  Missing frames: 41, 65. Each frame is also numbered 976.
- Documents relating to the Korean Emperor's tour in the south (Meiji 42-nen Kanko nanjun kankei shorui), 1909; 131 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 303.
  Missing frame: 94. Illegible fr.: 2-9. Each frame is also numbered 959. 1b, 40b, 54b-56 contain plans. 59, 104, 105 in Korean.
- Miscellaneous file, (Meiji 42-nen zassan ji shigatsu itaru junigatsu), Apr. - Dec. 1909; 81 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 304.
  Confidential documents relating to Ernest T. Bethell; the sale of the American Korean Electric Company in Seoul to Nikkan Gas Company; and the railroad connecting Korea with Manchuria. May 1 - Dec. 9, 1909.
  Illegible frames: 30-48, 50, 51, 54-56. Each frame is also numbered 947. 59b, 60a in Korean.
- Intelligence reports of the Korean Ministry of Internal Affairs, (Meiji 42-nenNaibu joho tsuzuri), 1909; 392 frames. (Reel 13)
  Box/Folder 6: 305.
  Documents relating to interrogation of the assassin of Prince Ito, An Chung-gun; public reaction in Korea toward the Imperial Court and the Japanese after the assassination; the Korean tour of a member of the Japanese Imperial Diet Ouchi Yozo; the activities of S0buk Hakhoe (Northwestern Association) and its leader An Ch'ang-ho, Horace G. Underwood, Homer B. Hulbert, and other American missionaries; the abolition of extraterritoriality in Korea; popular uprising in Korea; and the anti-Japanese political activities of Yu Tong-y0l, Yi Pak, Kim Hi-s0n, and Yang Ki-t'aek. Nov. 1 - Dec. 15, 1909.
  Missing frame: 73. Each frame is also numbered 945. Two different frames numbered 74. 81-83a, 114-116a, 124-127a, 213-215 contain tables; 64b, 65a contain diagrams. 213-215 in English.
- Documents relating to the spending of the Korean National Loan Redemption Fund, (Meiji 41-nen kokusai hoshokin shohi jiken), 1908; 299 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 306.
  Documents relating to the investigation of the case of the Korean National Loan Redemption Association Fund and the trials of Ernest T. Bethell, Yang Ki-t'aek, and others involved in it; and Anglo-Japanese negotiations concerning the trial of Bethell. July 17 - Oct. 2, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 888. 64, 65 on one frame. The contents of 202 and 203; 212 and 213; 219 and 220 are identical. 6a, 34-37a, 63-68, 138, 139a, 149-151, 153a, 183, 184a, 187, 202a, 203a, 210-212a, 213a, 218, 219a, 220a-270a in English.
- Annual report of the Kando Branch Office, (Meiji 42-nen Kanto hashutsujo nempo), 1909; 129 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 307.
  1908 annual report of the Chief of Kando (Chientao) branch office of the Residency-General, submitted on Jan. 9, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 948. 119-128 contain tables.
- The Ito disaster, (Meiji 42-nen Ito Ko sonan [no] ken), 1909; 69 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 308.
  Documents relating to the assassination of Prince Ito. Oct. 26 - 29, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 955. Two different frames each numbered 21 through 29; the second set is also numbered 29-1 through 29-9. 41b-44 in Korean.
- Documents relating to the Harbin Incident, (Meiji 42-nen Harupin jiken shorui), 1909; 159 frames. (Reel 19)
  Box/Folder 6: 309.
  Documents of the Japanese Residency-General in Korea relating to the assassination of former Resident-General Prince Ito. Correspondence between Japanese Foreign Minister Komura and Resident-General Sone relating to the arrest and trial of Ito's assassin, An Chung-gun, and his accomplices. Oct. 26 - Nov. 7, 1909.
  Missing frames: 112, 121. Two different frames numbered 113. Each frame is also numbered 949.
- Documents relating to the Harbin Incident, (Meiji 42-nen Harupin jiken shorui), 1909; 126 frames. (Reel 13)
  Box/Folder 6: 310.
  Documents relating to the assassination of Prince Ito, and the records of interrogation of his assassin, An Chung-gun, and other conspirators. Organizational chart of anti-Japanese parties in Korea. Jan. 4, 1910.
  Each frame is also numbered 950.
- Documents relating to the Harbin Incident, (Meiji 42-nen Harupin jiken shorui), 1909; 198 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 311.
  Documents relating to the interrogation of An Chung-gun, the assassin of Prince Ito, and his collaborators. Nov. 15, 1909.
  Missing frames: 78, 194. Each frame is also numbered 951.
- Reports of the [Japanese] gendarmerie on the Harbin Lacident, (Meiji 42-nen Harupin jiken kempeitai hokoku), 1909; 47 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 312.
  Secret Japanese gendarmerie documents relating to the investigation of the collaborators of An Chung-gun, the assassin of Prince Ito. Confidential report of Inspector-General of Korean Police Wakabayashi Raizo to Resident-General Sone concerning the Tae Han Hy0p'hoe (Korea Association) and the Ilchin'hoe party's joint investigation of the Korean government's responsibility in the assassination of Prince Ito; and the reaction to the death of Ito among Koreans at home and abroad. Nov. 17 - Dec. 3, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 952.
- Documents relating to the Harbin Incident, (Meiji 42-nen Harupin jiken shorui), 1909; 106 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 313.
  Documents relating to the Russian collaborators of the assassin of Prince Ito. An Chunggun, and to his trial. Jan. 5 - Mar. 22, 1910.
  Each frame is also numbered 953. Two different frames numbered 76.
- Documents relating to the Harbin Incident, (Meiji 42-nen Harupin jiken shorui), 1909; 31 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 314.
  Police reports to the Director-General of the Residency-General Ishizuka Eizo concerning the investigation of Koreans involved in the assassination of Prince Ito. Nov. 21 - Dec. 27, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 954.
- Copies of telegrams received, (Meiji 42-nen denju hikaetsuzuri), 1909; 78 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 315.
  Telegrams received from Japanese Foreign Minister Komura and others relating to the withdrawal of Japanese personnel and gendarmerie from Kando (Chientao); and the investigation of activities of Koreans in the Vladivostok area. Oct. 21 - Dec. 27, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 977.
- Copies of telegrams sent, (Meiji 42-nen denso hikaetsuzuri ji kugatsu itaru junigatsu), Sept. - Dec. 1909; 70 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 316.
  Telegraphic correspondence between Resident-General Sone and Japanese Foreign Minister Komura relating to Korean Manchurian boundary settlement and subsequent Sino-Japanese relations. Sept. 1 - Dec. 28, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 978.
- Correspondence of the Resident-General during his stay in Tokyo, (Meiji 43-nen Tokan jokyochu ofuku shorui), 1910; 114 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 317.
  Confidential correspondence of Resident-General Sone while on an official trip to Tokyo with his subordinates in Korea relating to the popular uprising near the Korean-Russian border; the interests of the First Bank of Tokyo in Korea; and the American and British missionaries in Korea, and the Korean Christians. The charter of the Korean American Commercial Company. Jan. 14 - Apr. 29, 1910.
  Illegible frame: 14. Each frame is also numbered 1009. Two different frames numbered 13. 31b, 102b in Korean.
- Report of an inspection tour of North Korea and Hwang'hae Province, (Meiji 43-nen hokkan oyobi Kokaido shisatsu fukumei), 1910; 104 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 318.
  Confidential inspection report by Imamura Takeshi of the Residency-General. Confidential monthly reports of the Japanese police in Kunsan, Inchon, and Taej0n relating to Korean political activity. Jan. 8 - Feb. 15, 1910.
  Illegible frame: 81a. Each frame is also numbered 1015. 91, 92, 94b, 95b, 96, 97b contain tables.
- Documents relating to local administrative reforms, (Meiji 43-nen chiho seido kaikaku), 1910; 39 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 319.
  A plan submitted by Korean Minister of Interior Pak Ch0ng-yang to Korean Premier Yun Yong-s0n concerning the reorganization of local administrative districts and changes in personnel. Aug. 2, 1896.
  Each frame is also numbered 1020. 7-39 in Korean.
- Documents relating to the dispatch of a secret mission to the Hague and the conclusion of the [Japanese] Korean treaty, (Meiji 40-nen Hagu misshi jiken oyobi Kan [sic] kyoyaku teiketsu), 1907; 268 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 320.
  Confidential correspondence between Resident-General Ito and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu relating to the secret mission sent by the Korean Emperor to the Hague Peace Conference and Russo-Japanese negotiations concerning Korea. Text of the Korean-Japanese Treaty of July, 1907. July 2 - Aug. 2, 1907.
  Missing frames: 39, 73. Illegible fr.: 222. Each frame is also numbered 1132. 34 is followed by 34-1. 12, 13, 20b-33, 34-1, 38, 51-59, 121-125, 145a, 198b-200, 213b-217, 222a, 232b-260 in English; 171-180, 204b in Korean.
- Class B documents of the Foreign Affairs Department [of the Residency-General] relating to foreign residents in Korea and other matters, (Meiji 39-nen otsushu Gaimubu gaijin kyoju sonota), 1906; 5 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 321.
  Communications between Korean Foreign Minister Pak Che-sun and Resident-General Ito concerning the official status of Durham White Stevens. Mar. 16 - Apr. 3, 1906.
  Each frame is also numbered 1097.
- Class B documents of the Foreign Affairs Department [of the Residency-General] relating to rites and ceremonies, custom duties and other matters, (Meiji 39-nen otsushu Gaimubu gishiki zeikan sonota), 1906; 8 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 322.
  Communications between Resident-General Ito and Director-General of the Residency-General Tsuruhara Sadakichi relating to the resignation of Korean Minister of Justice Yi Ha-y0ng and the Minister of Imperial Household. May 5 - June 14, 1906.
  Each frame is also numbered 1093. 8b in Korean.
- Class B documents of the Foreign Affairs Department [of the Residency-General] relating to Customs and other matters, (Meiji 40-nen otsushu Gaimubu zeikan sonota), 1907; 38 frames. (Reel 14)
  Box/Folder 6: 323.
  Documents relating to Korean students in Japan. July 15 - Oct. 28, 1907.
  Illegible throughout. Each frame is also numbered 1149.
- Documents concerning Koreans in the United States and Russia, (Meiji 39-41-nen Zai Bei-Ro Kanjin kankei), 1906 - 1908; 90 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 324.
  Confidential documents relating to the activities of Koreans in the United States and in Russia from 1906 to 1908. Dec. 21, 1906 - Sept. 4, 1909.
  Missing frames: 70-78. Each frame is also numbered 1190. Two frames each numbered 67 and 89. 49, 84b, 85a in Korean; 88a in English.
- Documents relating to the Shikigumi Company, and timbering in the Yalu River area, (Meiji 39-40-nen Shikigumi kankei Oryokko shinrin saibatsu [sic] kankei), 1906 - 1907; 119 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 325.
  Documents are dated from Dec. 8, 1904 - Aug. 10, 1909.
  Each frame is also numbered 1118. 73b, 74a contain tables. 70-73 in English.
- Class A documents of the Department of Foreign Affairs [of the Residency-General] relating to Customs and other matters, (Meiji 40-nen koshu Gaimubu zeikan sonota), 1907; 192 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 326.
  Confidential communication between Korean Prime Minister Yi Wan-yong and Resident-General Ito relating to Japanese police administration in Korea. Confidential documents relating to the activities of Pak Y0ng-hyo, Cho Chung-ung, and other Korean political leaders. June 9 - Nov. 10, 1907.
  Missing frames: 97, 98. Illegible fr.: 43b, 46a. Each frame is also numbered 1145. Two different frames each numbered 78 and 189. 3, 4a in Korean.
- Documents relating to Bethell [of] Tae Han Maeil Shinbo, (Meiji 39-40-nen Dai Kan Mainichi Shimpo Besseru), 1906 - 1907; 54 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 327.
  Confidential communications between Director-General of the Residency-General and the Japanese Adviser to the Korean Police Administration Maruyama Shigetoshi; and the Chief of the Korean Police Bureau Matsui Shigeru with the Director of Foreign Affairs of the Residency-General Nabeshima Keijiro and with Resident-General Ito: concerning Ernest T. Bethell's Tae Han Maeil Shinbo (Korea Daily News) and Korea Daily News and insurrection in various parts of Korea that occurred in response to Bethell's appeal. May 2, 1907 - June 12, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 1178. 8a, 20a in English; 19, 32b-36a, 48b-54 in Korean
- Documents relating to the observance of the Japanese-Korean Agreement, (Meiji 40-nen Nikkan kyoyaku riko kankei), 1907; 35 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 328.
  Confidential communications between Resident-General Ito and Japanese Prime Minister Saionji concerning the schedule and the method of abolition of the Korean Army. Texts of an agreement between Korea and Japan regarding the sending of Japanese naval forces for coast guard duty in Korean waters. Texts of the Russo-Korean agreement concerning the Russian naval station at Masan signed on Mar. 17, 1900. July 28 - Aug. 1, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 1143. 5-7, 20-22a in Korean.
- Miscellaneous documents relating to foreign affairs, (Meiji 40-nen gaiji zakken), 1907; 10 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 329.
  Documents relating to the dispatch of a special Korean ambassador to Japan to reciprocate for the visit of the Japanese Emperor's envoy to the coronation of Emperor Sunjong in 1907. Aug. 23 - Sept. 5, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 1142. 609 in Korean.
- Miscellaneous Class A documents relating to the Department of Foreign Affairs, [of the Residency General]; (Meiji 40-nen koshu Gaimubu zatsu), 1907; 13 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 330.
  Confidential documents relating to the publication of Tae Han Maeil Shinbo (Korea Daily News) and Korea Daily News. Note from Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu to Resident-General Ito regarding the treatment of Koreans by Japanese military personnel dated Nov. 29, 1907. Jan. 19 - Nov. 30, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 1146. 3b-5 in Korean and in English.
- Class B documents of the Department of Foreign Affairs [of the Residency-General] relating to foreign residents in Korea, (Meiji 39-nen otsushu Gaimubu gaikokujin), 1906; 23 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 331.
  Documents relating to an interview on Nov. 4, 1906 between a representative of Resident-General Ito and an American H. Collbran dealing with the Korean American Electric Company and other matters. Texts of an agreement between the Korean government and H. Collbran and H. R. Bostwick relating to the Korean American Electric Company signed on Feb. 4, 1904.
  Each frame is also numbered 1094. The contents of 1-6 and 7-12 identical. 13-23 in English.
- Class A documents relating to matters of protocol of the Korean Foreign Office, (Meiji 39-nen koshu Gaimubu gishiki), 1906; 20 frames.
  Box/Folder 6: 332.